<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dani's Braindump</title>
    <description>My thoughts about the world</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 09:57:17 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 09:57:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>GitHub Pages with custom plugins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been some time since &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/bye-bye-wordpress-hello-jekyll/&quot;&gt;I moved my blog from Wordpress to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. This blog is now hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GH pages&lt;/a&gt; and jusing &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, GH pages only supports a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/versions/&quot;&gt;limited subset&lt;/a&gt; of the many Jekyll plugins there are out there. This was not a problem until today, where I wanted to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ayastreb.me/jekyll-maps/&quot;&gt;Jekyll-Maps plugin&lt;/a&gt; to display post locations on a map. I need this plugin for my new category  &lt;a href=&quot;switzerland&quot;&gt;Swiss Frenzy&lt;/a&gt; on which I am placing locations from various posts on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing the plugin on my computer and running the server locally was no problem - the map showed up and everything else still worked nice too. However, pushing the changes to GH caused the build to break which resulted in the Blog not being updated. The URL under &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tiefenauer.info&quot;&gt;http://www.tiefenauer.info&lt;/a&gt; still showed the version before the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until today I could live with the few plugins that were supported. However, this might only be one of many plugins that I might want to use in the future. So I started looking for ways to mitigate the problem. Of course the easiest solution would be to build the site locally and only push the compiled files to GH. This would work since then GH would not recognize the repository as a Jekyll project, but merely a bunch of static HTML files - no building needed on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking for ways to do this and found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/jekyll-plugins-github/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by David Lyons, suggesting keeping source and compiled (site) files in separate directories and manually copying the files over from one directory to the other. However, this would most likely mean keeping the source files also in separate repositories. But I don’t want maintain two repositories for what  actually belongs together. Luckily I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/28249255/how-do-i-configure-github-to-use-non-supported-jekyll-site-plugins&quot;&gt;this question&lt;/a&gt; (linked from &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/36377865/locally-building-and-pushing-jekyll-site-to-github-pages&quot;&gt;this question&lt;/a&gt;) on StackOverflow. In the accepted answer the steps are required to keep both source and compiled files in the same directory and repository. The process is roughly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initialize an new repository with a remote pointing to your GH repository. You are now on master branch. Checkout a new branch &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up a new Jekyll project. Add some content (blog posts or the like).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build the Jekyll project. A new folder &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; is created containing the compiled site ready to be served. Ignore this directory by putting it in a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit the files. Since &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; is ignored the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/code&gt; branch will now contain only the source files, but no compiled files. You can now push this branch to GH pages. Since GH pages only serves from the master branch, you will not see anything when navigating to &lt;em&gt;http://username.github.io&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change to the newly created &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder and initialize another repository with &lt;strong&gt;the same remote&lt;/strong&gt; as in the first step. You are again in the master branch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.nojekyll&lt;/code&gt; file inside the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder preventing GH pages to build anything. While still in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder, commit and push this file together with the compiled source files (already there from the build in step 3). Since nothinng was commited before, the master branch now only contains the compiled files.The site will now be served from &lt;em&gt;http://username.github.io&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That way, you can keep working on the source files in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; branch (in the root directory) and push the files from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch (in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; directory). You only have to take care not to switch to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch in your root directory and accidentally commit any source files as this might trigger a Jekyll build on GH again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this method involves keeping separate branches of the same repository being checked out in different folder, this seemed the easies method for me. Unfortunately, the steps apply only when setting up a brand new blog with Jekyll. In my case, I already had a lot of source files on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch. I therefore had to adjust the steps a bit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ignore the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt;-folder (if not already done). Checkout a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;source&lt;/code&gt;-branch and push it to GH (no changes made). The master and the source branch in the remote repository are now identical. The master branch might trigger build errors, but we will solve that in the next steps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the project root directory checkout the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch again: Trigger a new Jekyll build to update the site files in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; directory: add a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.nojekyll&lt;/code&gt; file but do not initialize a repository here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the root directory: delete everything except the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder and some IDE-specific metafiles (which were gitignored in my case)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copy all files from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; one level up to the project root directory. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder should now be empty and can be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commit the changes (actually we have replaced the entire project) and push them to GitHub. Since the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch now only contains the compiled files, no builds are made and the newest site version (built in step 2) will be served. Because the build was run locally, there are no problems with unsupported plugins on GH.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copy all the compiled site files &lt;strong&gt;including the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/strong&gt; to a backup folder on your hard drive. Since we changed the commit history, we must also include the  &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Still in your project root directory: Switch back to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/code&gt; branch. All the source files should be there again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure there is no &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder (delete it, if there is). Create the folder manually and copy the compiled site files including the commit history from your backup folder. You now have the repository on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/code&gt; branch in your project root folder and the same repository on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-new-workflow&quot;&gt;The new workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebuilding the project on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/code&gt; branch in the project root will update the files in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; directory and therefore provide changes for the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch. Those changes can now be committed and pushed by changing to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; directory and committing/pushing from there. It is not as conveniend as always working in the same directory, but I think this effort is manageable. In detail, when writing new posts, the workflow is as follows from now on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create the post, including assets etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the project root directory: build the site and commit everything to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/code&gt; branch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; directory and commit/push the changes generated in the previous step to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been some time since &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/bye-bye-wordpress-hello-jekyll/&quot;&gt;I moved my blog from Wordpress to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. This blog is now hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GH pages&lt;/a&gt; and jusing &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, GH pages only supports a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/versions/&quot;&gt;limited subset&lt;/a&gt; of the many Jekyll plugins there are out there. This was not a problem until today, where I wanted to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ayastreb.me/jekyll-maps/&quot;&gt;Jekyll-Maps plugin&lt;/a&gt; to display post locations on a map. I need this plugin for my new category  &lt;a href=&quot;switzerland&quot;&gt;Swiss Frenzy&lt;/a&gt; on which I am placing locations from various posts on a map.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/gh-pages-plugins/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/gh-pages-plugins/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Bözingerberg and Taubenlochschlucht</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the locals of Biel the Bözingerberg is a popular destination to get out of the city for a while. Biel lies exactly on a language border and is famous for its watch industry and it is not uncommon to hear German and French in equal parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hike starts with a passage of 90 minutes uphill. A lot of path is in the forest, which is good especially in hot and humid weather. The Bözingerberg is actually accessible by car on a tarmaced road. That’s why the mountain is also popular for mountain bikers who take the easy way up. You are likely to encounter some downhill riders on your way up. The path leads you through a small park (&lt;a href=&quot;https://tierpark-biel.ch/&quot;&gt;Tierpark Biel&lt;/a&gt;) where you can watch/feed domestic animals (deer, ibex, marmots and the like) and have a picnic. On top there is a restaurant where you can have an ice cream or something (the Rösti also looked good :stuck_out_tongue:). You get a stunning view down to the Lake Biel and the Mittelland (flat region of Switzerland). On a clear day you can see the Alps. If you get bored you can always watch the paragliders take of, since the Bözingerberg is a popular (even official) starting place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way back is also through the forest for the greater part. The hike culminates in the last passage that takes you through the Taubenlochschlucht (&lt;em&gt;Pigeon Hole Gorge&lt;/em&gt;) along a creek. Note that the gorge is rather short, but still offers some stunning views and a pretty decent waterfall. There are also many caves (the pigeon wholes), some of which you can explore. But be aware that in some of them there are actually full of pigeons!. Also note that bathing in the creek is prohibited since there is a hydro station upstream which might open its gates suddenly. Back in Biel you can relax in the public seaside bath (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctsbiel-bienne.ch/&quot;&gt;Seebad Biel&lt;/a&gt;), which is very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pictures&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/frenzy/2018-06-02-boezingerberg/view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ice cream with a view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For the locals of Biel the Bözingerberg is a popular destination to get out of the city for a while. Biel lies exactly on a language border and is famous for its watch industry and it is not uncommon to hear German and French in equal parts.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/boezingerberg/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/boezingerberg/</guid>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>frenzy</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Seleger Moor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.selegermoor.ch&quot;&gt;Seleger Moor&lt;/a&gt; is a nice garden with lots of flowers between lake Zurich and lake Zug. The are is pretty rural there so it is easy to miss (I actually found out I had already driven past it a few times before). There is parking available so getting there should not be a problem. The park requires an entrance fee, so make sure to bring your wallet. If you like flowers however, your money will be spent wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the park you can walk, enjoy the many plants and spot the occasional frog or duck. You can also bring children as there is a playground and plenty opportunities to play hide and seek. There is also a picnic place where you can put something on the grill. But be sure to be there early (or late) enough as the park is also pretty popular in good weather.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.selegermoor.ch&quot;&gt;Seleger Moor&lt;/a&gt; is a nice garden with lots of flowers between lake Zurich and lake Zug. The are is pretty rural there so it is easy to miss (I actually found out I had already driven past it a few times before). There is parking available so getting there should not be a problem. The park requires an entrance fee, so make sure to bring your wallet. If you like flowers however, your money will be spent wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/seleger-moor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/seleger-moor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>frenzy</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Klöntalersee</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kloental.com/&quot;&gt;Klöntalersee&lt;/a&gt; is a small lake in the canton of Glarus. It is not near any major town, so you are pretty much in the wild there. There is a restaurant and a campground who I expect to be pretty crowded in summer. You can access the lake by car or motorcycle from the city of Glarus but be aware that this is a dead-end road during the weekends which means you have to drive back the same way you came from. Not a bad thing though, because the route is pretty scenic. Take your time though because the road can become very narrow which makes cornering a real challenge at times. Because of the campground you have to expect RVs behind every turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road continues and becomes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alpen-paesse.ch/de/alpenpaesse/pragelpass/&quot;&gt;Pragel pass&lt;/a&gt;, which connects the city of Glarus with the town of Muotathal. However, the pass is only open on weekdays which makes it very popular with cyclists on weekends, because they are the only ones allowed to pass. If you can, go during a weekday, because then the pass is open for general traffic. But be warned: the road is very adventurous, narrow and steep and the tarmac is not always the best. Beside a cheese dairy with a small restaurant there is not much up there. All the better to enjoy the wonderful nature around you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kloental.com/&quot;&gt;Klöntalersee&lt;/a&gt; is a small lake in the canton of Glarus. It is not near any major town, so you are pretty much in the wild there. There is a restaurant and a campground who I expect to be pretty crowded in summer. You can access the lake by car or motorcycle from the city of Glarus but be aware that this is a dead-end road during the weekends which means you have to drive back the same way you came from. Not a bad thing though, because the route is pretty scenic. Take your time though because the road can become very narrow which makes cornering a real challenge at times. Because of the campground you have to expect RVs behind every turn.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/kloentalersee/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/kloentalersee/</guid>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>frenzy</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Charging your phone wirelessly on your motorbike</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the weather was not terribly good on ascension this year, I tried to make maximal use of my time by starting a little crafting project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often go for shorter or longer rides with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yamaha-motor.eu/ch/de/produkte/motorrad/sport-touring/tracer-900.aspx&quot;&gt;my motorbike&lt;/a&gt; using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moto_G4&quot;&gt;mobile phone&lt;/a&gt; for navigation or tracking my rout (I have grown fond of &lt;a href=&quot;http://calimoto.eu&quot;&gt;Calimoto&lt;/a&gt; btw. which I can heartily recommend). For the ride I usually attach my phone to the  motorbike using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rammount.com/products/x-grip&quot;&gt;Ram Mount X-Grip&lt;/a&gt;, which is rock solid and holds the phone in position no matter the speed or terrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the problem with using GPS on your phone to do so is that it can quickly drain your battery. Luckily my motorcycle has a power outlet which allows me to plug in a USB adapter to charge my phone. But since I am a lazy rider I got tired of having to unplug the phone everytime I parked the bike only to plug it in again when I continue my ride. I looked for a more time-saving option thad didn’t involve wrapping cables around the handlebar or fiddling with the tiny USB ports on the phone. The solution was to upgrade my mount with a wireless charging capability which is cheap, easy to do and works surprisingly well, even if your phone does not support wireless charging (like mine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shopping-list&quot;&gt;Shopping list&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the following parts, most of which can be purchased from your trused &lt;del&gt;local&lt;/del&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://wish.com&quot;&gt;Chinese wholesale store&lt;/a&gt;. Click on the links to see exactly which parts I used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wish.com/product/5a449a3adaa5c75cc80b8efa&quot;&gt;wireless charger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wish.com/product/55bb70799e42592de0f327e0&quot;&gt;USB car charger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wish.com/product/59928e978d28360ab7e8a51c&quot;&gt;Shrink-Wrap tubes&lt;/a&gt; to&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plastidip-sale.com/&quot;&gt;Plasti Dip&lt;/a&gt; to make everything wateproof&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(optional) a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wish.com/product/5991599991c5c93d55d942bf&quot;&gt;wireless adapter&lt;/a&gt; if your phone does not support wireless charging out of the box (like mine)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(optional) a USB cable to attach to your motorbike permanently (you can use the one that came with your phone if you can spare it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(optional) a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wish.com/product/565fb962c8e6990453bf2349&quot;&gt;Y-cable&lt;/a&gt; for faster charging if your USB charger has two ports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;let-the-crafting-begin&quot;&gt;Let the crafting begin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first snapped open the wireless charger to expose its internal parts. Turned out it only consisted of a inductor which was glued to a thin, round metal plate and a small circuit board, both connected with two short cables. The metal plate was broken (probably when I opened the case), but that did not seem to affect functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/motorcycle_wireless_charging/wireless_charger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The opened wireless charger&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first removed the round plastic sticker which covered the base plate of the mount. I then first glued the metal plate to the mount and then the inductor to it. The sizes matched perfectly, so it almost looked like the parts were made for exactly this mount :smile:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/motorcycle_wireless_charging/ram_mount_collage.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Top left:&lt;/strong&gt; The mount with the plastic cover removed.
        &lt;strong&gt;Top right:&lt;/strong&gt; Gluing the metal plate to the mount... 
        &lt;strong&gt;Bottom left:&lt;/strong&gt; ... then the inductor on top... 
        &lt;strong&gt;Bottom right:&lt;/strong&gt; Fits like a glove!
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reattaching the plastic lid with the Ram Mount the mount looks almost like before the modifications (apart from the cables hanging out). A small test run indicated that everything worked as expected. This was important to know before I would make the whole thing waterproof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-it-waterproof&quot;&gt;Making it waterproof&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the modified mount will be permanently attached to the motorcycle (including the cable, circuit board and inductor, but without the USB charger) I had to make sure the damn thing won’t be affected by the weather. To protect the connections I used the shrink wrap tube (be sure not to let it get too hot as the electronics may be quite sensitive). The circuit board was covered with three layers of Plasti Dip which (apart from being waterproof) has the nice property of also acting as an insulator. I also covered the shrink wrap tube, the cable between circuit board and inductor and the area between plasic lid and inductor with some Plasti Dip to make sure it is absolutely weather-proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/motorcycle_wireless_charging/plasti-dip.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Top left:&lt;/strong&gt; Plasti Dip bottle.
        &lt;strong&gt;Top right:&lt;/strong&gt; Circuit board with Plasti Dip partially applied 
        &lt;strong&gt;Bottom left:&lt;/strong&gt; protecting the connections with s shrink wrap tube
        &lt;strong&gt;Bottom right:&lt;/strong&gt; the covered circuit board
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modified mount was then reattached to the handlebar and the cables were fixed with some straps. The loose end of the charging cable was covered with a protective cap and the USB charger stoved away unter the socius seat. To get a bit more power from my USB charger I also connected the Y-cable with both ports of the USB charger. I put the wireless adapter under the back cover of my phone and tested it with on a short test ride. Everything looked fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/motorcycle_wireless_charging/phone_mounted.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The phone mounted on the modified cradle. You can see it's charging :smile:&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bottom-line&quot;&gt;Bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some driving around with the navigation app turned on I can say that the charging power is enough to keep my battery level stable (but not really charging). I wouldn’t go on a ride with an almost empty battery though. Other people might see other results depending on the bike, the cable, the USB adapter or the phone but for me that’s not much of a problem though since I always returned from a days drive with more than 90% battery left. The mount is now permanently attached to the motorbike and the modifications are barely visible. The usability is now also great: Put your phone into the mount and you’re done! :thumbsup:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the weather was not terribly good on ascension this year, I tried to make maximal use of my time by starting a little crafting project.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/wireless-charger-for-motorcycle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/wireless-charger-for-motorcycle/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Belchenflue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belchenflue&quot;&gt;Belchenflue&lt;/a&gt; is a summit located on the border between the canton of Basel-Land and Solothurn. There is a twisting road over the Chilchzimmersattel nearby leading from Eptingen to Langenbruck that I have driven several times by motorbike without noticing the peak. From the road it is only 15 minutes to the top but I recommend you start in the quiet town of Langenbruck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest you start in Langenbruck and walk up from there. The path is well signed and leads you uphill for 2 hours. Some of the rout leads through forest and there are some nice spots to rest. If you prefer a restaurant there is the &lt;em&gt;Dürstel&lt;/em&gt; pretty much in the middle. On the summit you get a mind-blowing view of the Jura and the Mittelland. But be warned if you are afraid of heights: the summit ends in a vertical drop of some 100m. There is a handrail, but if you are afraid of heights, you might not feel well on the very top. There are also some caves called Drachenloch (&lt;em&gt;dragon hole&lt;/em&gt;) you can explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there you have the option for a small detour to the restaurant &lt;em&gt;Berghaus Oberbölchen&lt;/em&gt;, which is popular with motorcyclists especially in summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way back leads you along the Geissflue back to Langenbruck. There are again plenty of picnic places along the path where you can roast a sausage or explore the ancient ruins of fortifications built during WW1. If you’re lucky you might even spot some chamois who roam there. Back in Langenbruck there is a Kneipp path where you can refresh your feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pictures&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/frenzy/2018-05-12-belchenflue/tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;weird tree on the road&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/img/frenzy/2018-05-12-belchenflue/landscape.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pittoresque landscape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belchenflue&quot;&gt;Belchenflue&lt;/a&gt; is a summit located on the border between the canton of Basel-Land and Solothurn. There is a twisting road over the Chilchzimmersattel nearby leading from Eptingen to Langenbruck that I have driven several times by motorbike without noticing the peak. From the road it is only 15 minutes to the top but I recommend you start in the quiet town of Langenbruck.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/belchenflue/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/belchenflue/</guid>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>frenzy</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>New section: Swiss Frenzy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I added a new section in the main menu: &lt;a href=&quot;/frenzy&quot;&gt;Swiss Frenzy&lt;/a&gt;. The section provides tips and ideas for short trips inside Switzerland. It is not meant for tourists who only want to see the major attractions, but rather for locals who want to explore some nice spots off the beaten track in their own country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I added a new section in the main menu: &lt;a href=&quot;/frenzy&quot;&gt;Swiss Frenzy&lt;/a&gt;. The section provides tips and ideas for short trips inside Switzerland. It is not meant for tourists who only want to see the major attractions, but rather for locals who want to explore some nice spots off the beaten track in their own country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/swiss-frenzy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/swiss-frenzy/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Bye bye, Wordpress. Hello Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have hosted my personal blog using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; on my beloved &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synology.com/de-de/support/download/DS109+#utilities&quot;&gt;Synology 109+ NAS&lt;/a&gt; for a long time. The site has been running 24/7 on this hardware for many years now. But after adding content over the years, adding more and more plugins and upgrading PHP a few times I begann noticing performance deteriorate more and more. I never put it to test, but it seemed to me like the pages took longer and longer to load. In the end, page speed was sluggish at best. All the plugins and DB accesses (and PHP’s hunger for resources) took their toll on the performance. It looked like my NAS was not such a good fit for a PHP/MySQL-backed Wordpress blog anymore…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/synology_109_nas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;My devoted workhorse which has been hosting my blog until now...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things worse, Synology has stopped shipping major software updates for my NAS. It hasn’t received any update (apart from security patches) for a long time and still runs DiskStation 4.2 at the time, which includes an outdated PHP version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;exit-wordpress&quot;&gt;Exit Wordpress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the long page loadsall I didn’t deem this to be much of a problem for me. Especially considering I use this blog as my personal braindump which has only got small attention (although I did receive some comments or E-Mails from all around the world). Until recently, when warnings started to pile up in the Wordpress Admin-Dashboard, urging me to update to the newest PHP version. I wasn’t even able to install or upgrade certain plugins anymore since they require a higher version of PHP. Upgrading the PHP version would be possible in theory, but this would mean fiddling with the internals of the DiskStation software and potentially running into compatibility issues. Not my idea of fun. So I had to decide between two paths: Staying with the current state (with the danger of the site becoming inoperable due to deprecated software) or going for the radical path and migrating everything to a new host. I went for the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I didn’t find any solutions for free Wordpress Hosting that met my requirements I looked around for something simpler, less resource hungry, without a zillion plugins. Something lightweight and sleek. At the same time it should support some key features that I often use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Syntax highlighting for various languages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;support for LaTeX&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;support for advanced text formatting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;customizable design (without having to handcraft everything)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open and extendable (to some point)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Possibility to write online or offline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the search harder, it all should be free (as hosting on my own NAS is). And yeah, the page speed should also be higher. Dear Santa Clause…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;enter-jekyll&quot;&gt;Enter Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/jekyll_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jekyll logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then came &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is a static site generator and the underlying technology used by &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. It does not need a database and you can write your content using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll uses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shopify.github.io/liquid/&quot;&gt;Liquid Templating Language&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;Front Matter&lt;/a&gt; that you can use to add some logic to your site. Your files are then compiled by GH Pages and served as plain old HTML pages. And since all the files reside in a normal GitHub repository, I don’t have to worry about things like backup or versioning anymore. I can even apply the same workflow for blogging like I apply for coding (or as Tom Preston-Warner expressed it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html&quot;&gt;Blogging Like a Hacker&lt;/a&gt;). The few dynamic features I used, like comments, can easily be replaced by third-party services like &lt;a href=&quot;disqus.com&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;. Having never used Jekyll before, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/build-blog-jekyll-github-pages/&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt; insightful. I don’t have any long-term experience yet. Time will show how it all turns out, but what I have seen so far looks promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;migrating-from-wp-to-gh-pages&quot;&gt;Migrating from WP to GH Pages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration is never an easy endeavour, especially considering all the assets (text, images, code blocks, CSS,…). So I tried to automate as much as possible. Jekyll is really trying to help out here by providing a &lt;a href=&quot;http://import.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;wide range of available importers&lt;/a&gt;. Alas, the provided Wordpress-Importer was only able to generate HTML files, not Markdown. And it only imports posts and pages, no assets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I found a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benbalter/wordpress-to-jekyll-exporter&quot;&gt;WP plugin&lt;/a&gt; which did a fantastic job of converting all my posts and pages to Markdown files (including all the images in them). Unfortunately, the images are linked with their absolute paths (i.e. an URL pointing to the old location of the image). The pages also do not always look as expected when displayed in the new blog, but this is not neccessarily the plugin’s fault. Some content like automatic table of contents (TOC) on pages is generated on the fly by a plugin and can not be migrated easily. So there still is a lot of work do be done by hand. But at least I was able to move moste of the content in one go without major hiccups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step was the site’s new design. I was looking for something sleek and minimal. Luckily, Jekyll is themeable and there are a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/&quot;&gt;lot of readily available themes&lt;/a&gt; out there. I went for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brianmaierjr/long-haul&quot;&gt;Long-Haul&lt;/a&gt; theme by Brian Maier Jr., which seems to be a goot compromise between focus on the content while still being visually appealing. I had to touch up on the CSS, the Layouts and the Gems a bit to fit the appearance my needs, but I was able to keep the theme in its original design without too much tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the new Jekyll Blog is basically just a bunch of Markdown files blogging can be done locally by creating/updating the Markdown files and/or fiddling with the configuration files. The changes can be tested locally and then be pushed to GitHub. Testing the pages locally requires you to install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org/de/&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and a few gems. But since Windows &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/windows/&quot;&gt;is not officially supported by Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and I sometimes only want to make a few quick changes (typos or the like) I looked for an alternative solutions which lets me edit the content online without having to install anything. Of course I can always edit the files directly on GitHub, but I was looking for something more practical, maybe even something WYSIWYG. I found two alternatives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://prose.io/&quot;&gt;Prose.io&lt;/a&gt;, a free which is explicitly targeted at Jekyll sites and lets you edit your content with a simple online editor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcannon.com/&quot;&gt;CloudCannon&lt;/a&gt; which is a somewhat more sophisticated solution targeted for professional CMS providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently using CloudCannon, which is free for basic use and a bit more powerful than Prose.io. It even features nice things like shortcuts while editing (e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CTRL + D &lt;/code&gt; to delete a line). Let’s see if I stick with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aftermath of the migration is not over. There is still a lot to do, especially in making sure all the links work, the images all show up and the content is properly aligned. But so far I’m quite happy with my decision to move to GH Pages. I’m still trying to migrate all the comments to Disqus, but that might take a bit longer than expected…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
---
**Update**
Migration is over and I hope everything is in its right place now. The Simplicity of Jekyll/GitHub makes blogging is a breeze, so I don't miss my old Wordpress-Setup at all. I guess I should rename this post's title to _&quot;Bye bye, sluggish performance, security issues, database administration, data backup, plugin incompabilities, ... Hello Markdown, integrated version control, statelessness, ...&quot;_, but I guess that would be a bit too long... ;)
--&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have hosted my personal blog using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; on my beloved &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synology.com/de-de/support/download/DS109+#utilities&quot;&gt;Synology 109+ NAS&lt;/a&gt; for a long time. The site has been running 24/7 on this hardware for many years now. But after adding content over the years, adding more and more plugins and upgrading PHP a few times I begann noticing performance deteriorate more and more. I never put it to test, but it seemed to me like the pages took longer and longer to load. In the end, page speed was sluggish at best. All the plugins and DB accesses (and PHP’s hunger for resources) took their toll on the performance. It looked like my NAS was not such a good fit for a PHP/MySQL-backed Wordpress blog anymore…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-wordpress-hello-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bye-bye-wordpress-hello-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Machine Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a looong time since my last post… :frowning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I have started my master’s degree with a focus on Machine Learning. For preparation I have finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning/&quot;&gt;Andrew Ng’s course in ML&lt;/a&gt;. If you have never heard of this course and want to break into ML I think this is a fantastic starting point. The explanations are concise and clear even without prior knowledge. The course consists of a series of videos and accompanying programming assignments, for which you’ll need &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mathworks.com/products/matlab.html&quot;&gt;Matlab&lt;/a&gt; (or its open-source twin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/octave/&quot;&gt;Octave&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to come back to what I have learned and revisit individual topics I decided to write a summary in my own words. This also helped me to get my thoughts straight and memorize the content better. I figured someone else might be interested in it too, so I put it all online for you to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the summary &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tiefenauer.info/ml_de&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Note it’s only available in German. Maybe I will translate it to English someday if I have the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please drop me a comment if you find anything unclear or (god forbid!) you find a mistake. :thumbsup:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a looong time since my last post… :frowning:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/new-series-machine-learning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/new-series-machine-learning/</guid>
        
        <category>coursera</category>
        
        <category>machine learning</category>
        
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>BDD with JBehave (2/2): Advanced tests</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This entry is part 2 of 2 in the series &lt;em&gt;BDD with JBehave&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous article about BDD with JBehave, we learned about how to create a test using the JBehave story pattern that describes preconditions, events and the expected behavior. Due to its natural language, the story can even be understood by non-technical users. The test described the behavior of a digital radio when the on/off switch is being pressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test was very basic, but sufficient to illustrate the basic functionality. More often however, it is neccessary to describe behavior in a more complex manner, e.g. by specifying and evaluating parameters, chaining preconditions and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this second part of the article series about BDD and JBehave we will explore some of the more advanced functionalities of JBehave to create more sophisticated behavior driven tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;parameterized-tests&quot;&gt;Parameterized Tests&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When describing events and expected behavior, it is often useful to evaluate certain parts of the expectation description in the story. We did this implicitly before by stating the following expectation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Then the radio should be turned on&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and evaluating the expecation in Java to a boolean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;assertTrue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;radio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;isTurnedOn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if we wanted to evaluate the expectation in a more complex manner, e.g. by specifying the following test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this test we need to evaluate a part of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;When...&lt;/code&gt; part of the story in Java to use it to set the frequency (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;103.8&lt;/code&gt;) of the radio. We also have to evaluate a part of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Then...&lt;/code&gt; part of the story in Java to assert the fulfillment of our expectation (displayed value should be &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;103.80 FM&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, extracting parameters from textual descriptions is not hard at all with JBehave. As you remember from part 1 of the series, it is important that the String handed over to the annotation matches the string in the story. JBehave finds the annotated Java method for a textual description by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jbehave.org/reference/stable/annotations.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;regex-matching this string &lt;/a&gt;with the one found in the story file. Since a regex is used for matching, the annotation string can contain special characters that will translate to parameter names. The parameter values can be injected in Java by specifying method arguments of the same name:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parameters are defined as Strings in the story file, but can be any other type in Java, including object types. Type conversion is done automatically by JBehave, where possible using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jbehave.org/reference/stable/parameter-converters.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;built-in parameter converters&lt;/a&gt;. If this is not possible, you can write your own parameter converter, but this is not in scope for this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, the method parameters carry the same names and occur in the same order as specified in the annotation string. This is good practice but there may be cases where naming and/or order of parameters in Java may be different. That’s why JBehave includes the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@Named&lt;/code&gt;-annotation for parameter values:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@Named&lt;/code&gt;-annotation both name and/or order of parameter can become independent of the description in the story. However, having parameter names and order the same is good practice and also less verbose. I suggest keeping them in sync unless there’s absolutely no way to avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s update our Radio so that the user can tune to a frequency by adding the following code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run your test and voilà: The test succeeds! 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;example-tables&quot;&gt;Example tables&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In certain cases it can become necessary to feed different parameter values to the test in order to check different behaviour. For example: Let’s assume our radio has a display which can display the current station name, but which is limited to 10 characters. If a station name is longer than 10 characters, the name should be truncated down to 7 characters and appended with three dots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually an extension of a parameterized test and can be formulated similarly in the story by using an example table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The test will then be executed once for each row in the example table, having the parameter values set to their respective value from the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s try this out and extend our &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;RadioSteps.java&lt;/code&gt; with appropriate methods to match the story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also add the following methods to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Radio.java&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we run our test now, it will fail with the following message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;org.junit.ComparisonFailure: 
Expected :A reall...
Actual :A really long station name which will definitely not fit into the display&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure of this test is actually a good thing, since it gives us a chance to fix this and immediately check the result of our efforts – all in the name of test-driven development. 🙂 So let’s change the previously added &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;getDisplay()&lt;/code&gt;-method to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run the test again! It should become green like a cucumber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;composite-steps&quot;&gt;Composite steps&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it can be useful to chain certain preconditions together to formulate a test. For example, let’s revisit our first test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Given a digital radio
When I press the on/off switch
Then the radio should be turned on&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s assume if the radio is already turned on, it should be turned off by pressing the on/off switch again. We can write another test, which is similar to the above, but with an additional precondition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Given a digital radio
And the radio is already turned on
When I press the on/off switch
Then the radio should be turned off&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s also extend our RadioSteps.java with an additional method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@Given&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;the radio is already turned on&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;theRadioIsTurnedOn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;radio&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;aDigitalRadio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;radio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;isTurnedOn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;radio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;switchOnOff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two preconditions are now chained together i.e. executed in sequence in the order given by the story file. Composition of steps can also be achieved by using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@Composite&lt;/code&gt;-annotation in Java. We could use the following test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Given the radio is already turned on
When I press the on/off switch
Then the radio should be turned off&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with the following step:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@Given&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;the radio is already turned on&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@Composite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;steps&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Given a digital radio&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;theRadioIsTurnedOn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;radio&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;aDigitalRadio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;radio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;isTurnedOn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;radio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;switchOnOff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result would be identical.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This entry is part 2 of 2 in the series &lt;em&gt;BDD with JBehave&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bdd-with-jbehave-advanced-tests/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bdd-with-jbehave-advanced-tests/</guid>
        
        <category>BDD</category>
        
        <category>Java</category>
        
        <category>JBehave</category>
        
        <category>TDD</category>
        
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
